Jigesh Kapadia

SUMMARY

Software Engineer with over three years of professional experience in building and maintaining web applications using ReactJS, AngularJS, Python and PHP. Proven ability to adapt and learn new technologies in a short period of time with strong problem solving and troubleshooting skills.

SOFTWARE SKILLS

- ReactJS	- NodeJS	- HTML5
- AngularJS	- TypeScript	- REST API
- Python	- JavaScript	- GIT
DIID /I 1\	.0	T ' (TTI 4

PHP (Laravel)
JQuery
MySQL
Odoo 8.0
Linux (Ubuntu)
Bootstrap

EMPLOYMENT

Zensar Technologies, Pune

Dec 2021 – May 2022

Software Engineer

TheAA-Roads

The Automobile Association is a British based company that provides vehicle insurance, loans, motoring advice and other vehicle related services.

- Experience in designing and developing web applications using AngularJS and NodeJS.
- Closely worked with the system testing team for fixing high priority bugs during weekly built cycles.
- Enhanced client's website by adding new functionality per user requirements.
- Troubleshoot critical issues in the production environment and inform management with possible solutions.
- Used JIRA to resolve high priority bugs as assigned by the team lead.
- Gain extensive knowledge using the GIT repository.
- Coordinate with team members to brainstorm ideas and perform peer code reviews.

Mahavir Consultants, Mumbai

June 2019 - Dec 2021

Software Developer

TheBckspace

E-Commerce web application that allowed users to buy and sell shoes, accessories and customized products.

- Lead team of four members to a successful project release by delivering high quality applications.
- Implemented Front-End of the application per user requirement using ReactJS, Ajax and jQuery.
- Developed Restful API to support front-end of the application for mobile and web.
- Created automation scripts using Python to auto fill forms with product and billing information.

Indusguru Network Partner

The company provided software to help business experts and consultants find the best opportunities to apply their experience and talent to build a platform for peer-to-peer learning and professional development. My primary responsibility was to develop applications for various contractors, consultants and administrators.

- Used an open source javascript library called, PivotTable, to display data in table format.
- Integrated Chart.js library to display various interactive graphs and charts.
- Developed a web application and made it compatible for various devices including mobiles, tablets and desktops.
- Resolved performance related issues in application by decreasing page load time.
- Maintained and bug fix legacy applications developed in PHP (Laravel).

Alert Citizen

The main purpose of the project was to alert citizens regarding Covid updates and help with contact tracing.

- Theme integration using ReactJS as per the client's requirements.
- Used Bootstrap DataTables to display data dynamically and customized table filters.
- Maintained the web application by adding new features to it and fixing high priority bugs.
- Troubleshoot and resolve technical issues in the production environment with minimal impact to business users.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering (B. E.), Computer Engineering

2016 - 2019

University of Mumbai

Shah & Anchor Kutchhi Engineering College

Diploma, Computer Engineer

2013 - 2016

Maharashtra State Board of Technical Education, Mumbai Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel Polytechnic

CERTIFICATION

React + Redux Course 2021

Sololearn

A course including introduction on ReactJS Framework and Redux including concepts like JSX, Props, event handling, rendering components, DOM and many more.

Digital / Modern Application Development

2017

NPTEL – IIT Madras, Online

A course on developing web applications using HTML, CSS, JS, and Github.